Guide to the Roger W. Moss Collection of Manuscript, Original Art and Printed Material by and about Richard Shirley Smith
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
- Publications Designed or Illustrated by Richard Shirley Smith, Series II
  - A Love Affair. London: Andre Deutsch, Ltd., 1965., Buzzati, Dino, 1906-1972; Pp. [i-iv] [1-2] 3-299 [300]; 205 x 140 mm (Volume Moss no. 63)
    Translated by Joseph Green. Printed by D. R. Hillman & Sons, Ltd., Frome, Somerset. First English edition after the 1963 Italian edition titled Un Amore. 'Jacket Design by Richard Shirley Smith.' Bound in deep wine red book cloth with dust jacket.
  - A Fool in the Forest. London: Dennis Dobson, 1965., Clark, Leonard; Pp. [i-ii] [1-6] 7-158; 222 x 145 mm (Volume Moss no. 64)
    First edition. Printed by East Midland Printing Co., Ltd., Bury St. Edmunds, Suffolk. 'Jacket design by Richard Shirley Smith.' Twenty monotypes, two used twice internally and again on the dust jacket. Bound in yellow book cloth with dust jacket.
  - False Colors. London: Longmans, 1965., Heyer, Georgette, 1902-1974 (Volume Moss no. 65)
    Richard Shirley Smith designed this paperback cover based on an enlargement of his wood engraving [Bain no. 78], no additional information is available; a copy not located or examined.
  - Prospectus 1965. London: The Folio Society, Ltd., 1965., Folio Society (London, England); Pp. [1-2] 3-26 [27-28]; 212 x 140 mm (Volume Moss no. 66)
    The decorated rule on the front cover and the head piece on page 3 were engraved by Richard Shirley Smith [Bain nos. 79-80]. Stapled soft binding.
    Shirley Smith had not yet provided illustrations for a Folio Society book. That would soon change; see Paul Nash, Folio Fifty, entry no.24 above.
  - The Faith of Teilhard de Chardin. Translated by René Hague. London: Burns and Oates, Ltd., 1965., De Lubac, Henri, 1896-1991; Pp. [i-v] vi-ix [x] [1-3] 4-206; 222 x 145 mm (Volume Moss no. 67)
    Printed by William Clowes and Sons, Ltd. 'The engraving on the jacket is by Richard Shirley Smith' [Portrait of Teilhard de Chardin; Bain no. 81]. Bound in dark red book cloth with dust jacket.
  - Memoirs from the House of the Dead. Translated with a Preface by Jessie Coulson. London: Oxford University Press (World Classics #597), 1965., Dostoyevsky, Fyodor, 1821-1881; Pp. [i-v] vi-xiii [1] 2-361 [362-368]; 152 x 97 mm (Volume Moss no. 68)
    Printed by Vivian Ridler, printer to the University. Cover by Richard Shirley Smith (line drawing). Bound in blue book cloth with dust jacket.
  - Masters of Music: Mozart. London: Ernest Benn, Ltd., 1965., Young, Percy M. (Percy Marshall), 1912-2004; Pp. [i-iv] v-viii, 1-72; 220 x 137 mm (Volume Moss no. 69)
    Printed by the Bowering Press, Plymouth. First edition. 'Illustrated by Richard Shirley–Smith.' Bound in reddish orange book cloth with dust jacket.
  - Masters of Music: Handel. London: Ernest Benn, Ltd., 1965., Young, Percy M. (Percy Marshall), 1912-2004; Pp. [i-vi] vii-viii] 1-70 [71-72]; 220 x 143 mm (Volume Moss no. 70)
    Printed by the Bowering Press, Plymouth. First edition. 'The books are illustrated with attractive line drawings by Richard Shirley Smith.' Bound in reddish orange book cloth with dust jacket.
  - Masters of Music: Handel. New York: Cornerstone Library, 1968., Young, Percy M. (Percy Marshall), 1912-2004; Pp. [1-12] 13-96; 203 x 130 mm (Volume Moss no. 71)
    Reduced-scale reprint of the 1966 first edition. 'Illustrated by Richard Shirley–Smith.' The Ernest Benn cover not used, but a dozen of Shirley Smith's line drawings, several repeated in detail, were used. Perfect bound soft cover.
  - Masters of Music: Beethoven. London: Ernest Benn, Ltd., 1966., Young, Percy M. (Percy Marshall), 1912-2004; Pp. [i-iv], v-viii, 1-69 [70-72]; 222 x 140 mm (Volume Moss no. 72)
  - Masters of Music: Britten. London: Ernest Benn, Ltd., 1966., Young, Percy M. (Percy Marshall), 1912-2004; Pp. [i-iv] v-viii, 1-68 [69-72]; 222 x 140 mm (Volume Moss no. 73)
    Printed by the Bowering Press, Plymouth. First edition. 'Illustrated by Richard Shirley-Smith.' Bound in reddish orange book cloth with dust jacket.
  - Masters of Music: Debussy. London: Ernest Benn, Ltd.; New York: David White, 1968., Young, Percy M. (Percy Marshall), 1912-2004; Pp. [1-4] 5-76 [77-78]; 220 x 142 mm (Volume Moss no. 74)
    Set in 12 point Caslon Old Face and printed by the Bowering Press, Plymouth. First Edition. 'Illustrated by Richard Shirley Smith.' Bound in blue book cloth with dust jacket.
  - Masters of Music: Tchaikovsky. London: Ernest Benn, Ltd.; New York: David White, 1968., Young, Percy M. (Percy Marshall), 1912-2004; Pp. [i-ii] [1-4] 5-76 [77-78]; 222 x 142 mm (Volume Moss no. 75)
    Set in 12 point Caslon Old Face and printed by the Bowering Press, Plymouth. First edition. 'Illustrated by Richard Shirley Smith.' Bound in reddish orange book cloth with dust jacket.
  - Masters of Music: Haydn. London: Ernest Benn, Ltd.; New York: David White, 1969. Set in 12 point monotype Garamond and printed at The Press at Coombelands, Ltd., Addlestone, Surrey. First edition., Young, Percy M. (Percy Marshall), 1912-2004; Pp. [i-ii] [1-4] 5-78 [79-80]; 220 x 137 mm (Volume Moss no. 76)
    Set in 12 point monotype Garamond and printed at The Press at Coombelands, Ltd., Addlestone, Surrey. First edition. 'Illustrated by Richard Shirley Smith.' Bound in reddish orange book cloth with dust jacket.
  - Masters of Music: Stravinsky. London: Ernest Benn, Ltd.; New York: David White, 1969., Young, Percy M. (Percy Marshall), 1912-2004; Pp. [1-4] 5-80; 223 x 143 mm (Volume Moss no. 77)
    First edition. Set in 12 point monotype Garamond and printed at The Press at Coombelands, Ltd., Addlestone, Surrey. 'Illustrations by Richard Shirley Smith.' Bound in reddish orange book cloth with dust jacket.
  - Carols for the Twelve Days. Compiled and arranged by Percy Young. New York: Roy Publishers, c. 1969., Young, Percy M. (Percy Marshall), 1912-2004; Pp. [1-9] 10-96; 255 x 190 mm (Volume Moss no. 78)
    'Illustrated by Richard Shirley Smith.' Bound in orange book cloth over-printed with Shirley Smith's dust jacket design.
  - Margaret Clitherow (1556?-1586). Foreword by Philip Caraman, S.J. London: Burns & Oates, Ltd., for the Catholic Women's League, 1966., Claridge, Mary; Pp. [i-v] vi-x [xi-xii] 1-196; 222 x 145 mm (Volume Moss no. 79)
    First edition. Printed in Monotype Bembo by Billing & Sons, Ltd., Guildford. 'The engraving on the jacket is by Richard Shirley Smith' [Bain no. 84]. Engraving also appears as the frontispiece. Bound in red book cloth with dust jacket.
  - A Newman Companion to the Gospels. Sermons of John Henry Newman selected and schematically presented by Armel J. Coupet. London: Burns and Oates, Ltd., 1966., Coupet, Armel J.; Pp. [i-vi] vii-xi [xii] [1-3] 4-439 [440]; 223 x 150 mm (Volume Moss no. 80)
    Set in monotype Ehrhardt by the University Press, Aberdeen. First edition. 'The engraving on the jacket is by Richard Shirley Smith' [not in Bain]. See engraving list (Section IV). Bound in blue book cloth with dust jacket.
  - Small Corner. London: Dennis Dobson, 1966., Turner, Roy, 1927-; Pp. [1-6] 7-220; 203 x 137 mm (Volume Moss no. 81)
    First edition. Printed by Clarke, Doble and Brendon, Ltd., Cattedown, Plymouth. 'Jacket design by Richard Shirley Smith.' Bound in brown book cloth with dust jacket.
  - Metamorphoses. A Novel. London: Gerald Duckworth & Co., Ltd., 1966., Vaughan Williams, Ursula; Pp. [1-6] 7-190 [191-192]; 190 x 128 mm (Volume Moss no. 82)
    Printed by Billing & Sons, Ltd., Guildford and London. First Edition. Engraving by Richard Shirley Smith (uncredited) [Bain no. 77] used for dust jacket and frontispiece. Bound in yellow book cloth with dust jacket.
    Bain lists this title as published in 1965 and assigns the number 77 to Shirley Smith's 'Daphne' pearwood engraving. This must be an error because the first edition of Vaughan William's Metamorphoses was published in 1966 and is so listed here.
  - Grateful Caliban. London: Dennis Dobson, 1967., Clark, Leonard; Pp. [1-7] 8-107 [108]; 223 x 145 mm (Volume Moss no. 83)
    First edition. Printed by Garden City Press, Ltd., Letchworth, Hertfordshire. 'Jacket illustration [monotype] by Richard Shirley Smith.' Bound in pale yellow book cloth with dust jacket. Richard Shirley Smith's copy with his studio ex–libris.
  - A Point of Departure. Poems by Joyce Finzi with Wood Engravings Richard Shirley Smith. Cambridge: The Golden Head Press, 1967., Finzi, Joy, 1907-1991; Pp. [i-vi] [1] 2-42 [43-50]; 215 x 153 mm (Volume Moss no. 84)
    Printed by Crampton & Sons, Ltd., Sawston, Cambridge. First edition. Seventeen wood engravings [Bain nos. 11–27]. Detail of 'The Dark Tower' [Bain no. 23] used as a four side bleed on the front cover. Sewn soft binding.
    While staying with Shirley Smith and his first wife in the hills east of Rome, Joyce Finzi, widow of the composer Gerald Finzi, was working on a collection of poems entitled 'The division of one is two'. These inspired this series of wood engravings which, without being direct illustrations, added a visual counter-point to the theme of departure which runs through the whole collection. This was the first publication of Shirley Smith's suite of Rome engravings created in 1961.
  - Sir Roger de Coverly by Joseph Addison, Sir Richard Steele & Eustace Budgell. Edited by John Hampden, with wood-engravings by Richard Shirley Smith. London: The Folio Society, 1967., Addison, Joseph, 1672-1719; Pp. [1-6] 7-158 [159-160]; 226 x 148 mm (Volume Moss no. 85)
    Set in 11-point monotype Baskerville and printed by Richard Clay at the Chaucer Press, Bungay, Suffolk. The illustrations consist of a frontispiece portrait of Addison and Steele and 30 wood-engraved head pieces [Bain nos. 85-115], one used at the opening of each essay. Shirley Smith also engraved a decorative rule, which is used beneath each head piece and on the title page. Bound by W. and J. Mackay in quarter brown buckram, marbled paper boards, green end papers. Brown slip case.
    This book project––Shirley Smith's first for The Folio Society––would presage his later career as the illustrator of fine limited editions; it was also his first major commission for a large number of his engravings. The year 1967 would prove to be a turning point in his career.
  - Memoirs of a London Doll, written by Herself. New York: Macmillan Company, 1967., Horne, R. H., (Richard H.), 1802-1884; Pp. [i-vi] viii-xxx, 143 [144-146]; 213 x 145 mm (Volume Moss no. 86)
    Edited by Mrs Fairstar (Otherwise Mr Richard Henry Horne). Introduction and notes by Margery Fisher with four endpaper illustrations by Miss Margaret Gillies and additional engraved decorations by Richard Shirley Smith [Bain nos. 116-131]. First edition. Bound in white book cloth, over-printed to duplicate the dust jacket.
  - Garland, a little anthology of poetry and engravings. Cambridge: The Golden Head Press, 1968., Warner, Francis, 1937-; Pp. [4] 5-22 [23-24]; 241 x 142 mm (Volume Moss no. 87)
    Printed by R. I. Severs, Ltd., of Cambridge on Basingwerk Parchment set in Scotch Roman. Limited edition of 275 copies. Includes Shirley Smith's engraving "The Candle" on page 15 [Bain no. 133]. Sewn soft cover.
  - The Prince and the Puppeteer. A fairy story by J. C. Bretherton with engravings by Richard Shirley Smith. Salisbury: Compton Press, 1969., Bretherton, J. C. (John Christopher), 1925-; Pp. [1-16]; 250 x 187 mm (Volume Moss no. 88)
    The engravings [Bain nos. 137-142] were cut on lino and the edition limited to 1000 copies, 100 of which are signed by the author and engraver of which this is copy number no. 66. Stapled soft binding with semi-opaque protective cover.
  - The Periodical. Oxford University Press, Spring, Summer, Autumn, Winter, 1970., 217 x 140 mm (Volume Moss no. 89)
    Four covers featuring wood engravings by Richard Shirley Smith. ["Cupid's Progress" Bain nos. 161-164]. Stapled soft covers.
  - The Story of the Venetian Villas. London: Visual Publications, 1973., Shirley Smith, Richard; booklet 225 x 135 mm, box 240 x 160 x 55 mm (Volume Moss no. 90)
    Consists of booklet containing a general introduction to the series of four filmstrips compiled, annotated and photographed by Shirley Smith (225 x 135 mm pp. 64) and a box (240 x 160 x 55 mm) holding four filmstrip canisters. The booklet has been quarter bound in black book cloth with marbled paper-cover boards.
    In 1969 and 1970, while Shirley Smith was Head of the Art Department at Marlborough College, he travelled to the Vento to photograph art and architecture. A third expedition was made in 1971 and this set of four film strips was the result. While the effort was not a financial success, the experience of closely examining the works of Palladio, Veronese, and the sculptor Vittoria at such sites as Maser and the Villa Barbaro influenced his later murals and framed paintings.
  - The Poems of Percy Bysshe Shelley. Selected, edited, and introduced by Stephen Spender Illustrated with wood engravings by Richard Shirley Smith. Cambridge: Limited Editions Club, 1971., Spender, Stephen, 1909-1995; Pp. [i-iv] v-xxvii [xxviii] [1-2] 3-312 [313-316]; 280 x 178 mm (Volume Moss no. 91)
    Designed by John Dreyfus and printed at the University Printing House in Cambridge by Brooke Crutchley, Printer to the University. Forty-six engravings [Bain nos. 165-210]. Edition of 1500 copies signed and numbered by Shirley Smith of which this is copy no. 793. Quarter bound in leather with orange book cloth boards impressed with oval relief (60 mm) portrait of Shelley. Slip case. A copy of The Monthly Letter of the Limited Editions Club (December, 1971, no. 450) laid in.
    The Shelley project––commissioned by the Limited Editions Club in the United States in 1969 at the suggestion of John Dreyfus-- was printed in 1971 and reprinted by the Heritage Press in 1974. This was Shirley Smith's largest book project in terms of the number of commissioned wood engravings. He would later write, 'I think the word "masterpiece" originally referred to the piece of work, that divides the apprentice from the professional; in which case this was my "masterpiece" as regards engraving.' The Paintings & Collages, p. 10.
  - Wood engravings for Poems of Shelley by Richard Shirley Smith., 1971?; Shirley Smith, Richard (Volume Moss no. 92)
    Boxed set of forty-two of the forty-six Shirley Smith engravings for the Shelley project [Bain nos. 165-206] printed on individual sheets of Japanese paper by the artist in a limited edition of 25 boxed sets, numbered and signed, of which this is set number seven. The 42 engravings have been individually matted and boxed. See engraving list (Section IV).
  - The Poems of Percy Bysshe Shelley. Selected, edited, and introduced by Stephen Spender Illustrated with wood engravings by Richard Shirley Smith. Norwalk, CT, Heritage Press, 1974., Spender, Stephen, 1909-1995; Pp. [1-2] [i-iv] v-xxvi [xxvii-xxviii] [1-2] 3-313 [314]; 267 x 170 mm (Volume Moss no. 93)
    Designed by John Dreyfus in 13 point monotype Bembo. Reprint of the Limited Editions Club edition of 1971. Bound in blue book cloth, front cover die-stamped with 55 x 44 mm stylized papyrus plant motif; endpapers printed with enlarged detail of Shirley Smith's 'Flowery Wreath' [Bain no. 180]. Slip case. A copy of the Heritage Club Sandglass describing The Poems of Shelley laid in.
    There is a variant of the Heritage Press edition binding with plain white endpapers and boards printed with an enlarged detail in four-side bleed of 'Moths and Moon' [Bain no. 192]. There is no mention that this is a reprint of the Limited Editions Club edition.
  - The Poems of Percy Bysshe Shelley. Selected, edited, and introduced by Stephen Spender Illustrated with wood engravings by Richard Shirley Smith. Norwalk, CT, The Easton Press, 1974., Spender, Stephen, 1909-1995; Pp.[1-4] [i-iv] v-xxvi [xxvii-xxviii] [1-2] 3- 313 [314]; 267 x 170 mm (Volume Moss no. 94)
    Collector's Library of Famous Editions. Reprint (probably run with the Heritage Club edition) on cream-white vellum-finish paper from the Finch-Pruyn mill of Glen Falls, New York. Printed and bound by Lake Book, John F. Cuneo Co., Melrose Park, IL. Bound in gilt-stamped full maroon leather embossed with a floral pattern designed by George Herrick, gold moiré silk endpapers, satin marker ribbon and gilt edges. A copy of The Collector's Library of Famous Editions describing The Poems of Shelley laid in.
  - Philip Stanhope fourth Earl of Chesterfield, Letters to his Son. Selected, edited and introduced by James Harding, wood-engravings by Richard Shirley Smith. London: The Folio Society, 1973., Chesterfield, Philip Dormer Stanhope, Earl of, 1694-1773; Pp. [frontis] [1-2] 3-201 [202-204]; 227 x 140 mm (Volume Moss no. 95)
    The lithographic frontispiece reproduces William Hoare's painting of Stanhope c. 1743, now in the National Portrait Gallery. Set in 11-point monotype Baskerville with Old Face Open for display and printed in brown and black by W. and J. Mackay. Twelve wood-engraved head-and-shoulder portraits by Shirley Smith [Bain nos. 217-228], printed in pairs, in brown. Each is used twice, in a different combination, so there are twenty-four pairs in all. Bound by W. and J. Mackay in quarter black buckram with Cockerell marbled paper boards. Slip case.
  - Hero and Leander, a poem by David Burnett with engravings by Richard Shirley Smith. Printed privately by the Oxford University Press, 1975., Burnett, David, 1937-; Pp. [1-48]; 230 x 153 mm (Volume Moss no. 96)
    First edition. Edition limited to 200 copies signed by the author and engraver of which this is no.192. Lino engravings cut in 1969 [Bain nos. 143-160]. Sewn soft cover with pink paper wrapper.
  - The River Boy. Introduction by Lord David Cecil. London: Oxford University Press, 1976., Whistler, Theresa; Pp [i-xii] [1] 2-114 [115-116]; 222 x 140 mm (Volume Moss no. 97)
    Printed by offset lithography by Billing & Sons, Ltd., Guildford, London and Worcester. 'Illustrated by Richard Shirley-Smith'. Line drawings [color dust jacket and sixteen drawings, some used multiple times]. Bound in golden yellow book cloth with dust jacket.
  - The Closed Door. Sidcot, North Somerset: Gruffyground Press, 1977., Reeves, James; Pp. [12]; 240 x 165 mm (Volume Moss no. 98)
    First edition. Text handset in Walbaum, and printed letterpress in black and brown on handmade cream Twinrocker Sweetbutter paper by Claire van Vliet and Susan Johanknecht at Janus Press in Vermont. Richard Shirley Smith wood engraving of a mournful girl sitting on the floor [Bain no. 239]. Limited edition of 245 copies of which this is one of 165 copies reserved for the Gruffyground Press (Janus and Twinrocker divided the remaining 75 copies). Signed by Shirley Smith and James Reeves. Sewn soft cover of brown Fabriano Ingres paper. Extra print laid in (signed and numbered 4/60) by Shirley Smith. Also laid in an unsigned wood engraving by Simon Brett and a typed letter from Anthony Baker, the Press's proprietor, explaining the meaning of 'Gruffyground' and reporting James Reeves's death.
  - Baden Ian Dundonald Baker Born Rowberrow., 1977?; 150 x 100 mm (Volume 98a)
    Somerset, March 29th, 1900 Died Axbridge, Somerset, January 18th, 1922' folded paper (150 x 100 mm) utilizing Richard Shirley Smith's wood engraving of a mournful girl [Bain no. 239]. Following the Libanus Press publication of the Moss checklist, Anthony Baker sent RWM a copy of this memorial to his father [see also 100a].
  - In Praise of Erasmus., 1977; Shirley Smith, Richard; 302 x 211 mm (Volume Moss no. 99)
    A keepsake illustrated by Richard Shirley Smith and printed at the Libanus Press, Hermitage, Berkshire. Quarto single sheet (302 x 211 mm). Colophon on verso reads: 'This broadside was printed at the Libanus Press, Hermitage, Berkshire, in November 1977, and is limited to one hundred and fifty copies signed by the engraver. This is No. 88.' The text is handset in 18- point Perpetua type, printed on dampened Amalfi white laid paper on the artist's Albion handpress of 1860. Wood-engraved portrait of Erasmus [1965; Bain no. 82] above two paragraphs from In Praise of Folly (1508) with Shirley Smith's engraved 'cone ribbons' logo for Libanus Press [Bain no. 235] on verso. In original Libanus Press envelope.
    This keepsake marks the beginning of Richard Shirley Smith's long and fruitful association with Libanus Press. Michael Mitchell has been an important friend and collaborator over several decades. He exhibited Shirley Smith's work at his Katharine House Gallery, commissioned and published many of his illustrations and engravings, and expertly printed many of his books and bookplates.
  - Six Hampshire Epitaphs. Sidcot: Gruffyground Press, 1977., Pp. [8]; 160 x 237 mm (Volume Moss no. 100)
    Designed and printed in Bell type on an Albion press by George Tee at the Cernel Press, Cerne Abbas, Dorset. Published by Anthony Baker at the Gruffyground Press, Ladram, Sidcot, Winscombe, Somerset. The wood engraving on the title page is by Richard Shirley Smith ['Churchyard,' 1977; Bain no. 240]. 110 un-numbered copies printed on Portals mould-made paper and 20 un-numbered copies on Hosho handmade paper. Sewn with blue thread, into overlapping French-folded blue Mingei paper covers.
    According to Mark Askam, Gruffyground Press: A Bibliography, 1972-2007 (see item no. 36 above), there were two issues of this item, neither of which met Anthony Baker's exacting standards of printing. Only a few copies were distributed.
  - Six Hampshire Epitaphs. Sidcot: Gruffyground Press, 1977. (Volume Moss no. 100a)
    Sidcot: Gruffyground Press, 1977. Following the Libanus Press publication of the Moss Collection checklist, Mark Askam sent RWM one of the unbound copies of #100 which he called 'one of the better printed copies!'
  - "Coronation Rose Baker née Tooze, Born Oakford Bridge, Devon, April 30th, 1902 Died Sidcot, Somerset, April 24th, 1982.", 89 x 110 mm (Volume Moss no. 100b)
    Folded paper 89 x 110 mm Utilizing Richard Shirley Smith's 'Churchyard' wood engraving [Bain no 240]. Sent to RWM by Anthony Baker who printed it as a memorial to his mother. Not in the Moss Collection printed checklist.
  - Recalling the Goddess in Spring A.H. 1345. Libanus Press, Hermitage, Berkshire, 1978., Elliot, Alistair; 249 x 178 mm (Volume Moss no. 101)
    Pp. [1-4] sewn into paper folder. Copy 35 of a numbered edition of 200 copies signed by the author. The text is handset in 18-point Perpetua type and printed on Vélin Arches pur chiffon creme paper, on a treadle platen press of 1895. Richard Shirley Smith wood engraved 'cone and ribbons' logo for Libanus Press [1975; Bain no. 235] used on cover and colophon page. Included in Libanus Press, Daylight Jobbery (1985), affixed to card 12.
  - Azrael & Other Poems. Libanus Press, Hermitage, Newbury, Berkshire, 1978., Warner, Sylvia Townsend, 1893-1978; Pp. [1-20]; 290 x 198 mm (Volume Moss no. 102)
    First edition, Crown Quarto. Printed in hand-set 18 point Perpetua Italic. Limited to 200 numbered copies, one half printed on T. H. Saunders paper, the other on French Vélin Arches paper of which this is copy no. 140. Richard Shirley Smith's 'cone and ribbons' Libanus Press logo [1975; Bain no. 235] used on the colophon page and on the prospectus produced by the press, a copy of which is laid in. Sewn soft cover of uncut Barcham Green paper.
    According to the colophon, 'This collection of poems was first circulated in typescript by Sir Peter Pears at the Aldeburgh Festival in 1977. The author was approached for permission to print them in their present form and this was granted shortly before her death in May, 1978. This volume is dedicated to her memory.'